A Guide to the Executive Papers of Governor William Hodges Mann, 1910-1914
Library of Virginia
- Series II: Subject Files, 1899-1914., Extent: 24 boxes. (Box 31-54)
  The Education files document correspondence to/from Governor Mann and R.C. Stearnes, Secretary of the State Board of Education, and other members of the board. This correspondence involves meetings, quarterly reports, the Co-Operative Education Association of Virginia, the Normal School for Women to be established in Radford, and charges against Dr. P.B. Barringer, President of the Virginia Polytechnic Institute, for poor administration. Also significant are letters of recommendations for superintendents of schools for various localities.
  Files associated with the contamination of oysters involve oyster contamination in the Potomac River. Governor Mann appointed Dr. Mead Ferguson as bacteriologist and E.W. Magruder as chemist on the part of Virginia to serve in conjunction with the experts appointed by Gov. Philips L. Goldsborough, Maryland, and the U.S. government. Includes correspondence from Gov. Goldsborough; Thomas Parran, House of Representatives; the Commission on the Merchant Marine & Fisheries; E.W. Magruder; James Wilson & David F. Houston, U.S. Secretaries of Agriculture; W. McDonald Lee, Commissioner of Fisheries; Thomas S. Martin, U.S. Senate; and Dr. Meade Ferguson.
  Racetrack gambling in Norfolk became a controversial subject during Mann's governorship as Mann fought to stop illegal betting at the Jamestown Jockey Club in Norfolk. Includes correspondence to/from Mann and Judge Joseph T. Lawless, Norfolk Circuit Court; Samuel W. Williams, Attorney General; J. Sydney Smith, attorney; and R.C. Marshall, Commonwealth's Attorney. These files also include a copy of the court case between the Commonwealth and the Jamestown Jockey Club, Inc.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Adjutant General
    - 1910 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - 1911 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - 1912 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - 1913 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - 1914 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Coast Artillery Corps Election, 1910-1911 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Military Board Finances, 1910 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Appropriation Requests
    - 1911 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - 1912 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Central State Hospital, 1911 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - College of William and Mary, 1911 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Eastern State Hospital, 1911 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Southwestern State Hospital, 1911 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - State Board of Charities and Corrections, 1911 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - State Female Normal School, 1911 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - State Normal and Industrial School, 1911 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - State Normal and Industrial School for Women, 1912 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - University of Virginia, 1911 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Virginia Military Institute, 1911 (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Virginia Normal and Industrial School, 1911 (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Virginia Polytechnic Institute, 1911 (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Virginia School for the Deaf & Blind, 1912 (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Virginia State Epileptic Colony, 1911-1912 (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - Virginia State Library, 1911 (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - Virginia State School for Colored Deaf and Blind Children, 1911 (Box 31, Folder 25)
    - Western State Hospital, 1911-1912 (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - Attorney General
    - 1910 (Box 31, Folder 27)
    - 1911 (Box 31, Folder 28)
    - 1912 (Box 31, Folder 29)
    - 1913 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - 1914 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Education
    - Board of Education, 1910-1913 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Co-Operative Education Association of Virginia
      - Minutes, 1910-1911 (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - Quarterly Reports, 1911 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Normal School For Women, 1910-1911 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - School Superintendent Appointments
      - A, 1913 (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - B, 1910-1913 (Box 32, Folder 8)
      - C, 1910-1913 (Box 32, Folder 9)
      - D, 1912-1913 (Box 32, Folder 10)
      - E, 1912-1913 (Box 32, Folder 11)
      - F, 1910-1913 (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - G, 1913 (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - H, 1910-1913 (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - I, 1913 (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - J, 1913 (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - K, 1913 (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - L, 1911-1913 (Box 33, Folder 7)
      - M, 1910-1913 (Box 33, Folder 8)
      - N, 1911-1913 (Box 33, Folder 9)
      - O, 1913 (Box 33, Folder 10)
      - P, 1911-1913 (Box 33, Folder 11)
      - R, 1911-1913 (Box 33, Folder 12)
      - S, 1911-1913 (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - T, 1910-1913 (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - V, 1913 (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - W
        - 1910-1913 May (Box 34, Folder 4)
        - 1913 June (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Polytechnic Institute, 1910-1912 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Escape of John Moore from Nelson County Jail, 1910-1912 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Fifth International Conference on State and Local Taxation, 1911 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Ford Hotel Block Purchase, 1913 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Financial Statements
    - Dairy and Food Division of the Dept. of Agriculture and Immigration, 1911 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - State Normal and Industrial School, 1913 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Virginia Penitentiary, 1910-1913 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Virginia State Library, 1911 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - General Assembly
    - 1911 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - 1912-1913 (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - H.B. 281 - Requests for Passage, 1910 (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - H.B. 281 - Requests for Veto, 1910 (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - Legislation Under Consideration, 1911-1912 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Refusal to Call Extra Session, 1910 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Gettysburg Monument Committee
    - 1910 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - 1911 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - 1912 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - 1913 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Contracts, 1910-1913 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Legislation, 1911 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Honaker Boundary (Russell County, Va.), 1910 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Invitations, 1911-1912 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 1905-1913 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1910-1913 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Norton Charter Amendment (Wise Co., Va.), 1910 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Notary Applications
    - A, 1912 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - B, 1911-1913 (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - C, 1910-1912 (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - D, 1911-1913 (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - F, 1911-1913 (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - G, 1911-1913 (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - H, 1911-1913 (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - J, 1910-1911 (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - K, 1912 (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - L, 1911-1913 (Box 35, Folder 23)
    - M, 1910-1913 (Box 35, Folder 24)
    - N, 1913 (Box 35, Folder 25)
    - O, 1911 (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - P, 1911-1913 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - R, 1910-1912 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - S, 1911-1913 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - T, 1910-1912 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - V, 1912 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - W, 1911-1913 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Y, 1910 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Z, 1911 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Oyster Contamination
    - 1912 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - 1913 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - 1914 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Paid Bills
    - A, 1910-1913 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - B, 1910-1914 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - C, 1910-1914 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - D, 1910-1913 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - E, 1911-1913 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - F, 1910-1913 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - G, 1910-1913 (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - H, 1910-1913 (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - I, 1912 (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - J, 1910-1912 (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - K, 1910-1913 (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - L, 1910-1914 (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - M
      - 1910-1912 (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - 1913-1914 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - N, 1910-1913 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - O, 1910-1913 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - P, 1910-1913 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - R, 1910-1913 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - S, 1910-1913 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - T, 1910-1914 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - U, 1910-1912 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - V, 1910-1912 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - W, 1910-1913 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Y, 1910-1911 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Printed Material, 1910-1912 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Proclamations
    - 1910 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - 1911 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - 1912 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - 1913 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Racetrack Gambling in Norfolk
    - 1911 Feb.-March (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - 1911 April-June (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - 1911 July-Dec. (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - 1912-1913 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Recommendations
    - Auditor of Public Accounts
      - Cardwell, W.D., 1910 (Box 38, Folder 10)
      - Donohoe, S.R., 1910 (Box 38, Folder 11)
      - General, 1910 (Box 38, Folder 12)
      - Harris, J.M., 1910 (Box 38, Folder 13)
      - Moore, C. Lee, 1910-1911 (Box 38, Folder 14)
      - Smyth, W.F., 1910 (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Board of Agriculture (5th District)
      - Burch, T.G., 1912 (Box 38, Folder 16)
      - Gregory, J.W., Undated (Box 38, Folder 17)
      - Wilson, William T., 1912 (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - Dairy and Food Commissioner
      - Covington, T.S.D., 1911 (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Ferguson, Meade, 1911 (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Garrett, Paul, 1911 (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Pucell, Benjamin L., 1911 (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - Shelton, T.P., 1911 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Game Commissioner
      - Aldridge, Frederick M., 1912 (Box 39, Folder 6)
      - Blanton, R.W., 1912 (Box 39, Folder 7)
      - Hart, M.D., 1912 (Box 39, Folder 8)
      - Holbrook, E.R., 1912 (Box 39, Folder 9)
      - Roane, Richard B., 1912 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Judicial Circuit (15th)
      - Chichester, R.H.L., 1910 (Box 39, Folder 11)
      - Ennis, W.E., 1910 (Box 39, Folder 12)
      - General, 1910 (Box 39, Folder 13)
      - Haw, George P., 1910 (Box 39, Folder 14)
      - Moncure, E.C. 1910 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - Southwestern State Hospital Board of Directors - Killinger, George G., 1910 (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - Staff Vacancy
      - Cunningham, E.L., 1911 (Box 39, Folder 17)
      - Hix, C.H, 1911 (Box 39, Folder 18)
      - Mount, W.D. & Galtchins, J.L., 1911 (Box 39, Folder 19)
      - Myers, H.S., 1911 (Box 39, Folder 20)
      - Pitts, A.L., Jr., 1911 (Box 39, Folder 21)
      - Rogers, C.W., 1911 (Box 39, Folder 22)
      - Tillett, T.R., 1911 (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - Rejected Applications for Pardons & Removal of Political Disabilities
    - A, 1911-1913 (Box 39, Folder 24)
    - Bailey-Blankenship, 1910-1913 (Box 39, Folder 25)
    - Booker-Bryant, 1910-1914 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Buck-Butt, 1910-1913 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Cadle-Cochran, 1910-1914 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Coleman-Cunningham, 1910-1914 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Dalton-Donson, 1910-1913 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Dorton-Dyson, 1910-1913 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - E, 1910-1914 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - F, 1910-1914 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Gaillord-Grayson, 1910-1913 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Green-Guynn, 1910-1912 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Haley-Hill, 1910-1913 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Hines-Hodges, 1910-1913 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Holberg-Hutchinson, 1910-1914 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - I, 1910 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - J, 1910-1913 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - K, 1910-1913 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Laine-Lewis, 1910-1913 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Light-Lloyd, 1910-1913 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Logan-Lyons, 1910-1913 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Mack-Meekins, 1910-1914 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Miller-Myers, 1910-1913 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - N, 1910-1913 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - O, 1910-1913 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Painter-Payne, 1910-1913 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Peebles-Pullon, 1910-1914 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Q, 1911 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - R, 1910-1914 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Saul-Shumaker, 1910-1913 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Silvers-Sprouse, 1910-1913 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Staples-Swank, 1910-1912 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - T, 1910-1913 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - U, 1910-1913 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - V, 1911 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Waddey-West, 1910-1913 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Whitaker-Woodson, 1910-1913 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Woodward-Wright, 1910-1913 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Y, 1910-1913 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Unidentified, 1910-1913 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Reports
    - Auditing Committee, 1910-1911 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Miller Fund, 1912 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - State Accountant, 1911-1912 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - State Board of Charities and Corrections
      - Committment of Ripley Children to the Care of the Children's Home Society, 1911 (Box 44, Folder 12)
      - Convict Road Force, 1911 (Box 44, Folder 13)
      - Eastern State Hospital, 1911 (Box 44, Folder 14)
      - Laurel Industrial School, 1911 (Box 44, Folder 15)
      - Virginia Home and Industrial School for Girls, 1910 (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - State Board of Dental Examiners, 1912 (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Staff Correspondence, 1911-1914 (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - United Agricultural Board of Virginia
    - Boys Corn Club, 1911-1913 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence
      - A, 1910-1913 (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - B, 1910-1913 (Box 45, Folder 3)
      - C, 1910-1913 (Box 45, Folder 4)
      - D, 1910-1913 (Box 45, Folder 5)
      - E, 1910-1914 (Box 45, Folder 6)
      - F, 1910-1913 (Box 45, Folder 7)
      - G, 1910-1913 (Box 45, Folder 8)
      - H, 1910-1913 (Box 45, Folder 9)
      - J, 1910-1911 (Box 45, Folder 10)
      - K, 1910-1914 (Box 45, Folder 11)
      - L, 1910-1913 (Box 45, Folder 12)
      - M, 1910-1913 (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - O, 1910-1911 (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - P, 1910-1911 (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Q, 1910-1913 (Box 46, Folder 4)
      - R, 1911-1913 (Box 46, Folder 5)
      - S
        - 1910-1911 June (Box 46, Folder 6)
        - 1911 July-1912 May (Box 46, Folder 7)
        - 1912 June-1913 Oct. (Box 46, Folder 8)
        - 1913 Nov.-1914 (Box 46, Folder 9)
      - T, 1910-1913 (Box 46, Folder 10)
      - U, 1910 (Box 46, Folder 11)
      - W, 1911-1913 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Farmer's Cooperation Demonstration Work Local Aid Memorandums, 1912-1913 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Legislation, 1910-1912 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Minutes, 1910-1913 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1910-1913 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Receipts, 1911-1914 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Statement of Vouchers Approved for Payment, 1910-1911 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Vouchers
      - No. 1-50, 1911 (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - No. 51-100, 1911 (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - No. 101-150, 1911 (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - No. 151-200, 1911 (Box 47, Folder 10)
      - No. 201-250, 1911 (Box 47, Folder 11)
      - No. 251-300, 1911 (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - No. 301-350, 1911 (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - No. 351-400, 1911 (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - No. 401-450, 1911 (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - No. 451-500, 1911-1912 (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - No. 501-550, 1912 (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - No. 551-600, 1912 (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - No. 601-650, 1912 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - No. 651-700, 1912 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - No. 701-740, 1912 (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - No. 741-760, 1912 (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - No. 761-775, 1912 (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - No. 776-800, 1912 (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - No. 801-850, 1912-1913 (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - No. 851-900, 1913 (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - No. 901-950, 1913 (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - No. 951-1000, 1913 (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - No. 1001-1033, 1913 (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - No. 1034-1060, 1913 (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - No. 1061-1100, 1913 (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - No. 1101-1150, 1913 (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - No. 1151-1200, 1913-1914 (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - No. 1201-1250, 1914 (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - No. 1251-1299, 1914 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Mineral, Timber, and Historical Exhibit, 1911 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Penitentiary
    - 1910 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - 1911 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - 1912 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - 1913 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Undated (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Convict Lime Board
      - Advertising Bills, 1912-1913 (Box 52, Folder 8)
      - Catalogues, 1909-1912 (Box 52, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence
        - 1911 (Box 52, Folder 10)
        - 1912 Jan.-Apr. (Box 53, Folder 1)
        - 1912 May 1-8 (Box 53, Folder 2)
        - 1912 May 9-15 (Box 53, Folder 3)
        - 1912 May 16-31 (Box 53, Folder 4)
        - 1912 June-Nov. (Box 53, Folder 5)
        - 1913-1914 (Box 53, Folder 6)
      - Railroad Rates, 1911 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Publications from Other States 1899-1910 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Tax Commission, 1911 (Box 54, Folder 3)
- Oversized
  - Correspondence (Alphabetical)
    - A-H, 1910-1913. (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - J-R, 1910-1913. (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - S-W, 1910-1913. (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Subject Files
    - General Assembly, 1913. (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1911. (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Paid Bills, 1911-1912. (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Proclamations, 1910-1912. (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Rejected Applications for Pardons, 1911-1913. (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - United Agricultural Board, 1911-1913. (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Penitentiary, 1911-1912. (Box 56, Folder 7)